#### NICHOLAS N WILSON

#### Software/Data Engineer, Neuroscience and Computer Science Graduate

% https://nickynw.github.io

■ nicknwilson@outlook.com

nickynw nickynw

in linkedin.com/in/nicknwilson/

♥ London, UK

#### **SKILLS**

For a full outline of relevant skills see my Software Portfolio

Python: Pandas, Numpy, NLTK, Regex, Matplotlib, Pyspark, SQLAlchemy Languages: Python, Typescript/Javascript, Java, SQL, Cypher, HTML/CSS Frameworks: FastAPI, Flask, Django, React

Cloud/DevOps: Docker, AWS, GCP, Azure, Jira, Git/Github, Dataiku Data: Snowflake, Neo4J, Postgres, MongoDB, Firebase, SQLite

#### **STATEMENT**

I am a highly motivated individual with a strong educational background in Neuroscience and Computer Science. My passion lies in exploring the emerging technologies of the modern era, having gained experience in Neuroinformatics, Virtual Reality, Data Pipelines/Big Data, Natural Language Processing, and Cloud Technologies. I consider myself a creative and versatile individual who seeks out opportunities to innovate, learn new skills and develop tools to benefit others. As of June 2023, I am pursuing a role where I will be able to utilise and expand on my core skillset in Python, packages, frameworks, cloud, and data.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Data Engineer/Software Engineer CausaLens, Causal Al Software Company

**#** 06/2022 - 12/2022

- **♀** Lyric House, London, UK
- Part of a team developing software to allow creation and maintenance of data pipelines for users. This involved the use of multiple proprietary frameworks, Graph Databases, SQLAlchemy/SQL Databases, FastAPI, and Docker for containerisation of various microservices.
- Providing data ad hoc using different methods such as FTP, external APIs or BeautifulSoup/Automated scraping.

# Data Engineer/Senior Data Engineer Curve Analytics, Consultancy Startup

## 05/2020 - Senior 09/2021 - 04/2022

- Aldwych House, London, UK
- Led the design and implementation of a data pipeline to support the creation of a quality control dashboard for an external client. This integrated data across multiple sources, enhanced through natural language processes such as Sentiment Analysis and Multi-label Classification via Google Cloud Platform. Dataiku and Microsoft Azure formed part of this infrastructure.
- Was the leading Full-Stack Software Engineer in the Digital Technology and Innovation Team as part of a hybrid role, driving the development of multiple internal products to support the Data Analytics team at Curve with their own specialised software for data and natural language processing, and collecting and integrating data from multiple external APIs.
- As line-manager to three junior data-engineers, I work closely
  with them to support the design and implementation of several ETL projects for both external clients and internal datascience capabilities. As part of this role I also aim to ensure
  high standards of coding and coordinated ways of working
  across the data team.

#### **EDUCATION**

MSc Computer Science with Distinction

**1** 09/2018 - 11/2019

- **Q** University of Bristol, UK
- 75% average mark across all modules
- Elected course representative and liaison, communicating students issues and their feedback to the university.

#### BSc Neuroscience with First Class Honours

**#** 09/2015 - 09/2018

- **♀** University of Bristol, UK
- 76% average mark across all modules
- Elected Events Coordinator in 2nd year to organise, plan and budget events for the Neuroscience Cohort (160+).

#### **PROJECTS**

(2023) Software Portfolio at https://nickynw.github.io

Static React site deployed via Github Pages.

#### (2023) MCQBOT at https://github.com/nickynw/mcqbot

Python API, graph database & React frontend for a multiplechoice quiz generator, with attention to modular design, containerisation, version control, object-orientated programming, automated testing, continuous development and code quality. Deployed via Google Cloud Run/Artifact and AWS Amplify.

#### (2022) Art Portfolio at https://visnickart.com

My personal Fine Art portfolio deployed via AWS Amplify.

#### (2020) Mixed Portfolio at http://nickynw.com

Dynamic React Site with MongoDB database, Express JS, deployed using Amazon EC2 instance (Ubuntu/Linux).

#### (2020) Unchained at https://github.com/nickynw/unchained

React Native Mobile app with Firebase database, Google Maps API, Google AdMob, and published via Expo.

#### (2020) Qbot (Defunct)

Dynamic Flask/Django site with Neo4j/Postgres database deployed via Heroku.

### (2019, MSc) Does the integration of Haptics into Virtual Reality enhance shared experiences of Parkinson's?

10min educational VR experience using Unity and Oculus Go focused on Parkinson's, exploring effects of integrated haptics on memory, empathy and immersion in VR.

# (2018, BSc) The effects of L-type calcium channel blocker nifedipine on non-REM electroencephalographic rhythms in mice

Final dissertation analysing EEG Data with Matlab, and quantitative analysis with SPSS, focusing on changes in sleep wave patterns in mice relating to Schizophrenia.